# SURESH PATTA

- SURESHNANI86@GMAIL.COM
- h +91-8374026999
- Hyderabad, INDIA

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative Senior Software Engineer offering 8+ years of experience and proficient in C#, ASP.Net, MVC, React and Agile/SCRUM methodology. Enthusiastic about developing forward-thinking solutions to tomorrow's productivity problems. Resourceful and adaptable approach to challenges. Highly effective at developing new programs and fixing problems with existing systems. Ability to decide in a rapid environment and make priority calls based on the situation. Ability to work independently as well as in a team context. Looking forward to joining a growing entrepreneurial organization.

### CAREER INTEREST

- Team Lead
- Project Lead

### **SKILLS**

- C#
- ASP.NET
- MVC
- React
- Node & Express
- Microsoft SQL Server
- Oracle
- jQuery
- JavaScript
- WCF & WPF
- RESTful API's
- Unit Testing
- Microsoft Visio

#### **EDUCATION**

 Bachelor of Technology -Computer Science and Engineering - Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

### DOMAINS WORKED

- Claims
- Providers
- Energy
- Retail
- Shipping

#### **WORK HISTORY**

Optum Global Solutions (India) Private Limited - Associate Software Engineering Manager

Hyderabad, TG • 09/2016 - Current

- Designed, implemented and monitored web pages and sites for continuous improvement in a fast-paced environment.
- Worked on an Agile (Scrum) Development Team to deliver regular updates to the business team and project managers.
- Analyzed requirements and designed, developed and implemented software applications for multiple websites.
- Introduced methodologies and best practices to enhance product definition and application customization.
- Adjusted software parameters to boost performance and incorporate new features for meeting customer needs.
- Applied optimization techniques to reduce page size and load times to enhance user experience.
- Performed the System Testing, Regression Testing for Complete UI after fixing the Issues which are reported by the Testing Team.
- Provided oversight to the 25-person team, discussed project roadblocks to drive issue resolution and promoted use of best practices.

# TEKsystems - Allegis Group Company - Senior Developer Bengaluru, KA • 02/2016 - 08/2016

- Participated in requirements gathering and design development meetings.
- Reworked applications to meet changing market trends and individual customer demands.
- Worked with a quality assurance team to set up scripts, test cases and automation protocols.
- Reviewed code and debugged errors to improve performance.
- Performed troubleshooting, diagnostics and analysis to uncover root malfunctions.
- Collaborated with users to gather requirements and evaluate ease of use.
- Kept the project manager informed of milestone updates and provided a detailed project report every 24 hours.

### **INDUSTRIES WORKED**

- Health Care
- Energy
- Retail
- Logistics

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Professional, Academy for Healthcare Management (PHAM)-AHM250
- Certified DevOps Professional

### **OPEN TO TRAVEL**

Yes

# Meditab Software (India) Pvt. Ltd. - Senior Programmer Analyst Ahmedabad, GJ • 10/2014 - 01/2016

- Responded to and remedied critical issues that could not be addressed by junior members of the team.
- Evaluated multiple software solutions during early software architecture plotting and system migration planning stage.
- Worked in team-driven environments and communicated effectively with all stakeholders.
- Participated in design sessions with clients to ascertain all project specifications for applications, databases and systems.
- Modified existing software systems to enhance performance and add new features such as HTML5.
- Communicated highly technical concepts using easily understood terminology.

## Infosys BPO - Senior Process Executive

Hyderabad, TG • 03/2014 - 07/2014

- Investigated basic issues and fixed code.
- Optimized reporting process to reduce expense and increase efficiency.
- Developed scripts to communicate with back-end servers in order to provide real-time updated information.
- Identified issues in software processes and implemented optimization techniques, resulting in 20% increase in productivity.

### IBX Technologies - Software Engineer

Bengaluru, KA • 11/2011 - 03/2014

- Discussed project progress with customers, collected feedback on different stages and directly addressed concerns.
- Tested troubleshooting methods devised innovative solutions, and documented resolutions for inclusion in the knowledge base for support team use.
- Worked closely with other business analysts, development teams and infrastructure specialists to deliver high availability solutions for mission-critical applications.
- Researched, designed and implemented scalable applications for information identification, extraction, analysis, retrieval and indexing.
- Rapidly prototyped new data processing capabilities to confirm integration feasibility into existing systems.
- Created proof-of-concept prototype applications for demonstration and evaluation purposes.
- Implemented unit and integration testing protocols to consistently deliver high quality, functional features with minimal defects.
- Developed custom software solutions for 3 clients.